David Pinos

Toronto, ON Canada (437) 262-0097 davidspinosp@gmail.com

Profile

Software Engineer with a background in Computer Science and Economics. Experience in software development, database design, data analysis, machine learning, and econometrics. Driven by a strong desire to excel in the technology industry, I am committed to continuous learning and consistently exceeding expectations.

Education (Sept 2018- May 2022)

Bachelor of Science, double major in Computer Science and Economics - University of British Columbia Coursework: Software Engineering, Machine Learning, Financial Economics, Databases, Networks

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, SQL, R, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git
- Frameworks and Libraries: Flask, Selenium, Pandas, NumPy, Sickit-learn
- Database Design, Data Analysis, Statistical Modelling

Work Experience

Software Developer - (Nov 2022 - Present) ONxpress Transportation Partners

- My responsibilities include developing software to meet business requirements and integrating
 existing systems into new pipelines.
- Tasked with identifying the tools and requirements to incorporate DevOps CI/CD into the SDLC.
- Created internal applications for office attendance management and Key Performance Indicator (KPI) tracking, enhancing coordination and empowering data-informed decision-making.

Machine Learning Intern - (May 2022- Aug 2022) Altscore

- Architected and developed a Python library which streamlined the customer acquisition process.
- Utilized machine learning models, including XGBoost and logistic regression, to perform accurate credit scoring, contributing to enhanced risk assessment and decision-making.

Analytics and Al Intern - (June 2021-Aug 2021) Kin Analytics

- Collaborated on the development and optimization of a client-facing API, resulting in enhanced service capabilities and reduced response time.
- Effectively processed and interpreted large-scale datasets, employing advanced techniques for visualization and training machine learning models.

Projects

AVSummary - (April 2023)

- Developed and hosted a Flask-based web application on Google Cloud Platform (GCP), integrating the Google Speech to Text API and the OpenAI API for summarizing audio.
- Implemented user authentication and enabled the storage of past transcriptions, utilizing a PostgreSQL database.

Grocery Sale Forecasting – (April 2022)

- Developed a Python program leveraging Recurrent Neural Networks to accurately predict sales.
- Successfully selected and incorporated a bidirectional Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) architecture, achieving the desired level of performance with a minimal test error rate.

Awards

Deputy Vice Chancellor Award - (Sep 2021) University of British Columbia

Scholarship awarded to continuing international students based on academic achievement